Guide to the Jason Rogers papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Newspaper Business, 1874-1948
  - Subseries V.1: Newspaper Associations, 1910-1948
    Some of Rogers's greatest contributions came from his advocating wider cooperation between journalists. This subseries contains files related to the origins of the Audit Bureau of Circulations. It also holds records from some publishing conferences.
    - Audit Bureau of Circulations, 1911-1927
      - Correspondence, 1911-1927 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Clippings, 1913-1931 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Business Documents, 1910-1948 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Press Associations, 1913-1929 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Subseries V.2: Newspaper Research, 1874-1932
    This subseries holds a small selection of historical advertisements, as well as clippings on journalism history. Subjects in these folders include Henry Ford and Victor Lawson, founder of the Chicago Daily News. There is some information on the Pressman's Strike of 1919, and on the larger question of the price of newsprint.
    - Advertisements, 1874-1929 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Chicago Daily News, 1888-1932
      - Appraisal of Chicago Daily News, 1888-1932 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Clippings--Victor Lawson, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Slides, undated, (4 slides) (Box 14)
    - Clippings--Journalism, 1916-1930 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - International Paper Co. vs. Jason Rogers, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Print Paper Crisis, 1916-1921 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Sound Merchandising Bill, 1918-1919 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pressman's Strike, 1919-1920 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Barbour's Reference Rate Service, 1921-1922 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Advertising Maps, 1925-1929 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Business Publications, 1928-1931 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Clippings--Henry Ford, 1927-1930 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Personal, 1825-1971
  This series holds documents related to the personal lives and business activities of Jason Rogers and his son, Walter Shillaber Rogers.
  - Subseries VI.1: Jason Rogers, 1825-1951
    This subseries holds business papers and clippings related to Rogers's career. It also has some research Rogers conducted into the life of John Dillingham, a nineteenth-century resident of Cape Cod. Dillingham's will of 1825 is also here.
    - Clippings--Biographical, 1894-1951 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Jason Rogers Photo, circa 1920 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Contracts, 1917-1930 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Clippings--Reviews, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - John Dillingham, 1825-1929
      - Will, 1825 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Clippings, 1908-1929 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Expense Journal, 1900-1925 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Jason Rogers Inc., 1924 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Subseries VI.2: Walter Rogers, 1919-1971
    Walter Rogers was an engineer, an advertising executive, and a naval officer. This subseries contains records from his education, business life, and documents a decades-long conflict with the military over his pension.
    - Schooling, 1919-1927 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Classical High School Yearbook, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Military Records, 1935-1971 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Engineering and Patents, 1939-1942 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Walter Rogers Photo, circa 1945 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Who's Who in the East, 1952-1954 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Typescript--Captain Baker, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 15)